All right. So, we are we covered
operators, but I want to show you
something really cool called compound
operators. So, um we talked about um
addition, subtraction, multiplication,
and division and the modulus operator.
And for the first four, I am going to
show you something called compound
assignment. If we created a variable,
we'll say let um fancy number equal
equal three.
Let's say I wanted to add three to that.
Hopefully you remember that you can just
say fancy num plus three. So that's how
you'd add it to alert it. But maybe we
want to store that information. So I
could create a new variable here. I
could say let my new num equal
fancy number plus three. And now if we
alert my new number, then we should get
three + 3 is six. So we should get six
if we
pop over to our web browser.
Oh, I apologize. I was using a different
thing. So, I need to close my server,
restart my server, and now we get six.
Okay, so hopefully that's nothing too
scary. You remember how to do addition
hopefully. Um, so
what we've done though is we've created
a variable and then we created another
variable um just to get the number six.
And maybe we don't want to do that on
multiple lines. So, and maybe we don't
want to use multiple variables. So,
we're going to start first by getting
rid of our extra variable. So, rather
than saying let my new number equal my
fancy number plus three, why don't we
just overwrite what was in my fancy
number? So, my fancy number was three
and then we added three to that to get
six. And if we assign it back to itself,
then it will be updated from being three
to being six. So, let's do that. So
we'll say fancy num equals fancy number
plus three. And now when we alert fancy
number we should see six. So if we pop
over we see six. We reload our page we
see six exactly like we were expecting.
So we said take the three
and call it fancy number. Then take that
fancy number and add three which will
give us a total of six and store that
back inside of fancy number. So now when
we get to this line, fancy number is
six. So now we've cut down the number of
variables we're using. There's a way to
cut it down even further so you're not
using multiple lines of code. Rather
than saying this equals itself + 3,
there's a shorthand notation for this
because um we don't like typing that
much. So we'll say fancy number plus
equals 3. What that's saying is take
fancy number, add three to it, and then
store it back. So you can see the plus
and the equals are still here, but it
saves us from having to type fancy
number twice.
Line 19 and line 21 are exactly the same
functionalitywise.
This is just a shorter way of doing it.
So what we're saying is take what was
already in fancy number, add three to
it, and then save it.
So just to prove this is the case, we'll
comment out this line. So this is a
three and we're saying take what's
already in the variable, meaning three,
add three to it and save it. Which means
when we alert, we should get a six. So
if we save this and we come over here,
there's our six from last time. If we
reload our page, we get a six again. And
that is because of compound assignment.
So compound assignment doesn't just work
with addition. You can do it with
multiplication and division um and
subtraction. So if I wanted to say fancy
number
fancy number equals fancy number time
two that would say take what's in there
multiply it by two and then store it. I
could write that on one line by saying
fancy num multiply equals 2.
line 23 and line 24 are the exact same
thing.
We can do it with division. So if we
said fancy number equals fancy number
divided by two,
that's uh we would say take what's
already in there divided by two and then
store it back. So write that in
shorthand. Say fancy number equals fancy
number sorry fancy number divide equals
2.
And just to really hit the point home,
we're going to do it again with
subtraction. If you're really bored, you
can skip the end of this video. Um, all
we're doing is with subtraction. So if
we want to do a subtraction, we say
fancy number equals what's already in
fancy number minus 2. to write that
shorthand. Fancy number minus equals
fancy number or sorry fancy number minus
equals 2. Line 29 and 30 exactly the
same lines. Line 26 and 27 exactly the
same lines as each other. Lines 23 and
24 are the exact same lines. Lines 19
when it's not commented and lines 21 are
exactly the same lines. compound allows
us to quickly uh do in shorthand what
would have taken us a long time to
write. This is really helpful when you
have really long variable names, but
describe what's being held in the
variable. Um then you don't have to type
them over and over and over. Uh
hopefully that um explained how compound
assignment works. And that's the end of
this video. Thanks for watching.